RG 129, Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company
Connecticut State Library
Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company records
1829-1906
Connecticut State Library
Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company (Conn.)
37 cubic feet
The Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company was chartered in 1828 with John Fitch as its first president. It ceased to exist in 1906 when, according to the Connecticut Insurance Commissioner’s Report, it transacted no business and all of its policies had expired.
RG129
T001343
Historical Note
The Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company was chartered in 1828 with John Fitch as its first president. It ceased to exist in 1906 when, according to the Connecticut Insurance Commissioner’s Report, it transacted no business and all of its policies had expired.
Scope and Content
The collection contains annual statements, journals and ledgers, a register of policies, insurance policies, treasurer’s accounts, and other financial records.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company (Conn.)
Subjects:
Tolland County Mutual Fire Insurance Company (Conn.)-- Records and correspondence; Insurance companies -- Connecticut -- Tolland County -- History -- Sources; Fire insurance -- Connecticut -- Tolland County -- History -- Sources; Insurance -- Connecticut -- Tolland County -- History -- Sources
Document Types:
Account books; Check stubs; Insurance claims; Insurance policies; Journals (accounts); Ledgers (account books); Registers (lists)
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1829-1906
  - 1. Journals, 1854 June 1-1901 December 30; 10 volumes
    - 1854 June 1-1861 April 10 (Volume Item 1)
    - 1861 April 12-1866 June 6 (Volume Item 2)
    - 1866 June 1-1870 February 28 (Volume Item 3)
    - 1871 March 3-1876 March 30 (Volume Item 4)
    - 1876 April 1-1880 May 31 (Volume Item 5)
    - 1880 June 1-1883 December 31 (Volume Item 6)
    - 1884 January 1-1887 May 25 (Volume Item 7)
    - 1887 June 1-1893 April 30 (Volume Item 8)
    - 1893 May 1-1898 December 16 (Volume Item 9)
    - 1898 December 19-1901 December 30 (Volume Item 10)
  - 2. Ledgers, 1854-1901; 5 volumes
    - 1854-1866 (Volume Item 11)
    - 1866-1872 (Volume Item 12)
    - 1872-1881 (Volume Item 13)
    - 1882-1889 (Volume Item 14)
    - 1890-1901 (Volume Item 15)
  - 3. Annual statements, proxies, etc. (Box Box 16)
  - 4. Treasurer's account of assets and liabilities, 1833-1873 (Volume Item 17)
  - 5. Check stubs, 1874 December 5-1879 May 26 (Volume Item 18)
  - 6. Cash, expense and commission accounts, 1871 June-1901 December 31
    - 1871 June-1877 January (Volume Item 19)
    - 1877 January-1888 May (Volume Item 20)
    - 1888 June-1902 April (Volume Item 21)
  - 7. Orders for payment of insurance, 1851-1862 (Volume Item 22)
  - 8. Accounts with various agents, 1901-1906 (Volume Item 23)
  - 9. Register of policies, 1829-1847, 1852-1901
    Arranged chronological by policy number.
    - Index (Oversize Item 24)
      Covers policy no. 1-4230
    - No. 1-4126, 1829-1847 (Volume Item 25)
    - No. 7441-14476, August 1852-1861 July (Volume Item 26)
    - No. 14477-20129, 1861 August-1866 January (Volume Item 27)
    - No. 20130-26660, 1866 February-1869 August (Volume Item 28)
    - No. 26661-33563, September 1869-1873 July (Box Item 29)
    - No. 33564-40260, 1873 August-1876 May (Volume Item 30)
    - No. 40261-46422, 1876 June-1879 March (Volume Item 31)
    - No. 46423-52634, 1879 April-1882 April (Volume Item 32)
    - No. 52635-58684, 1882 April-1884 December (Volume Item 33)
    - No. 58685-65237, 1885 January-1887 August (Volume Item 34)
    - No. 65238-72094, 1887 August-1890 May (Volume Item 35)
    - No. 72115-78980, 1890 May-1893 April (Volume Item 36)
    - No. 78981-85830, 1893 April-1895 March (Volume Item 37)
    - No. 85831-92694, 1895 March-1896 September (Volume Item 38)
    - No. 92695-99337, 1896 October-1898 April (Volume Item 39)
    - No. 99338-106175, 1898 April-1899 October (Volume Item 40)
    - No. 106176-110916, 1899 October-1901 November (Volume Item 41)
    - Index no. 8, 1889 June-1895 January (Volume Item 42)
      Covers policy no. 69723-89272.
    - Index no. 9, 1892 January-1895 January (Volume Item 43)
      Covers policy no. 75132-89261.
    - Index no. 2, 1862 June-1876 January (Volume Item 44)
      Covers policy no. 15280-40260.
    - Index no. 2, 1876 June-1888 June (Volume Item 45)
      Covers policy no. 40262-69711.
    - Register pf policies renewed, 1853 September-1901
      - 1853 September-1861 June (Volume Item 46)
      - 1861 May-1892 March (Volume Item 47)
      - 1892 April-1893 December (Volume Item 48)
      - 1897-1901 (Volume Item 49)
  - 10. Policies, 1829 January 14-1856 July 22
    Chronological by policy number.
    - No. 1, 1-595, 1829 January 14-1836 January 13 (Volume Item 50)
    - No. 2, 596-912, 1836 January 13-1838 March 14 (Volume Item 51)
    - No. 3, 913-1225, 1838 March 14-1839 February 19 (Volume Item 52)
    - No. 4, 1226-1391, 1839 February 19-1839 December 11 (Box Item 53)
    - No. 5, 1392-1550, 1839 December 11-1840 August 12 (Volume Item 54)
    - No. 6, 1551-1853, 1840 August 19-1841 September 8 (Volume Item 55)
    - No. 7, 1854-2187, 1841 September 14-1842 September 12 (Volume Item 56)
    - No. 8, 2188-2517, 1842 September 14-1843 November 9 (Volume Item 57)
    - No. 9, 2518-2896, 1843 November 8-1844 December 26 (Volume Item 58)
    - No. 10, 2897-3235, 1844 November 15-1845 October 8 (Volume Item 59)
    - No. 11, 3236-3588, 1845 October 8-1846 June 10 (Volume Item 60)
    - No. 12, 3589-3938, 1846 June 10-1847 February 18 (Volume Item 61)
    - No. 13, 3939-4248, 1847 February 19-1847 September 8 (Volume Item 62)
    - No. 14, 4249-4535, 1847 September 8-1848 May 10 (Volume Item 63)
    - No. 15, 4536-4830, 1848 May 6-1849 January 10 (Volume Item 64)
    - No. 16, 4831-5112, 1849 January 10-1849 July 3 (Volume Item 65)
    - No. 17, 5113-5402, 1849 July 3-1849 November 24 (Volume Item 66)
    - No. 18, 5403-5692, 1849 November 24-1850 March 30 (Volume Item 67)
    - No. 19, 5693-5975, 1850 March 30-1850 September 11 (Volume Item 68)
    - No. 20, 5979-6283, 1850 September 11-1851 January 23 (Volume Item 69)
    - No. 21, 6284-6591, 1851 January 23-1851 June 16 (Volume Item 70)
    - No. 22, 6592-6894, 1851 June 11-1851 November 12 (Volume Item 71)
    - No. 23, 6895-7237, 1851 November 12-1852 April 14 (Volume Item 72)
    - No. 24, 7238-7440, 1852 April 14-1852 August 11 (Volume Item 73)
    - No. 25, 7441-7784, 1852 August 1-1853 January 3 (Volume Item 74)
    - No. 26, 7785-8130, 1853 January 1-1853 July 15 (Volume Item 75)
    - No. 27, 8131-8479, 1853 July 18-1854 February 8 (Volume Item 76)
    - No. 28, 8480-8831, 1854 February 8-1854 August 22 (Volume Item 77)
    - No. 29, 8832-9180, 1854 August 22-1855 February 3 (Volume Item 78)
    - No. 30, 9181-9534, 1855 February 7-1855 July 12 (Volume Item 79)
    - No. 31, 9535-9880, 1855 July 20-1855 December 13 (Volume Item 80)
    - No. 32, 9881-10221, 1855 December 13-1856 April 30 (Volume Item 81)
    - No. 33, 10222-10423, 1856 April 30-1856 July 22 (Volume Item 82)
  - 11. General account of policies issued, 1847 June-1856 June (Volume Item 83)
    Covers policy no. 4127-10297.
  - 12. Transferred policies issued, no. 1, 1845 June 30-1894 December 4 (Volume Item 84)
  - (Volume No item 85)
  - 13. Cancelled policies
    - 1851 June-1878 December (Volume Item 86)
    - 1879 January-1901 November (Volume Item 87)
  - 14. Record of losses of policies issued
    - 1869-1898 (Volume Item 88)
    - 1898-1902 (Volume Item 89)
  - 15. Proofs of loss
    - 1859 June-1885 (Box Box 90)
    - 1886-1892 (Box Box 91)
    - 1883-1897 (Box Box 92)
    - 1898-1900 (Box Box 93)
    - 1901- 1902 September (Box Box 94)